WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
(BELL RINGS)
Who will groan first when
they see it, Granny or Papa?
(CHUCKLES) I should think they'll
howl at the moon in unison.
What in God's name is this?
Well I never! Where did this come from?
I ordered it in London,
picked it up on the way back.
It's an AC. Well, at least it's English.
Welcome back, my darling.
How was the honeymoon? My eyes
have been opened. Don't I know it!
Anna get back all right? Yes.
Who's that for? Why are
you doing it down here?
It's for Mr Matthew. It
was creased, I'm ironing it.
You're never looking after
him? What about Mr Molesley?
He's staying at Crawley
House. Why wasn't I asked?
Mr Carson thought it best. Did
he? I wonder how that came about?
If you're learning your job,
never open a shirt in a room
where it might be marked,
let alone put studs in it.
Do that in a dressing room
and nowhere else. Thank you.
Yes, you're always trying
to be so very helpful.
How did you enjoy the south
of France? It was lovely,
but almost too hot, even now.
It's a shame they close things
in the summer. I love the sun.
So we can see. You couldn't be in
Cannes in summer, it's unbearable.
I could. Just how long is she here for?
Who knows? No guest should be admitted
with no departure date settled.
You won't get any argument from me.
There's a hideous pile of post.
I've put it on the hall table.
Don't look at it tonight.
What have you been up to?
I've found myself a new occupation,
but Violet doesn't think it's appropriate.
Can we talk about it afterwards?
Are there still forbidden subjects
in 1920? I can't believe this.
I speak of taste rather than law.
Well, it's not my taste.
What about you, Cora? I agree with Mama.
Some subjects are not
suitable for every ear.
Oh, pas devant les domestiques.
Come on, my dear, Carson and Alfred
know more about life than we ever will.
Can't we stop this? How?
She's like a runaway train.
Why do you call him poor
or old? He's neither.
Isn't it dangerous to let this
Strallan nonsense simmer on?
To be fair, I don't think it's
coming from him. Ask him to end it.
He'll be more effective than if we try.
Ooh, she ate it, then?
Never sure about Americans and offal.
She'll eat whatever you put
in front of her. What a gob.
Mr Carson was going to
put a bag over her head.
Oops. Mrs Levinson
knows you make fun of her
because she makes fun of
you. We're all square, then.
It's not drying properly,
the oven's not hot enough.
A bad workman always blames his tools.
Are you busy? No. We're eating
in half an hour but it's all done.
Well, if you could spare a minute.
This is very good, you didn't
open it for me. Certainly I did.
To welcome you into this house as my son.
I can't tell you how glad it makes me.
I want us always to feel we
can be honest with each other.
Of course. Because Mary's told me
about your present difficulties.
Oh, she was right,
losing Downton will affect
you both more than anyone.
Has she told you about the
will of Lavinia's father?
Yes, your father told me all about it,
but I cannot understand why so
much money was put into one company.
I couldn't agree more. Now we're
to be turned out of Downton.
Even Lloyd George can't want that.
I'm not sure he's a good example.
The point is have we overlooked something,
some source of revenue
previously untapped?
If only we had some
coal, or gravel, or tin.
I can think of someone
who's got plenty of tin.
So you help women who have... fallen over?
Not quite. Isabelle helps women
who have to degrade themselves
to survive. There's a centre in York.
No addresses, please.
Alfred will make notes.
What do you do for these women?
First, we like to send them away...
to rest. I should think they need it.
And then we try to find
them alternative employment.
The War destroyed many households,
thousands of bread winners died.
So you want me to contribute?
You don't have to give money
after every conversation. No?
Isn't that what the English
expect of rich Americans?
Why can't you benefit from the
will? You've done nothing wrong.
He didn't know I'd broken
his daughter's heart.
It was to reward my fidelity
when in fact I'd betrayed her.
If I kept that money, I'd be no
better than a common criminal.
I see.
If that's how you feel,
there's no more to be said.
I'm ever so sorry, my lord, I
thought you were out of here.
We should be. Please. We're going now.
It's a lump, there's no
point dithering about that.
What are you going to do
about it? I don't know.
Tomorrow, you'll make an appointment
with the doctor and see what he says.
But what if it's... If it
is, and I'm not saying it is,
it's best to know now.
I suppose so.
Now, look, you'll not be alone for
a minute if you don't want to be,
but we have to get it seen to.
Then there's expense.
If you must pay money, better
to a doctor than an undertaker.
If that's an example of your
bedside manner, Mrs Patmore,
I think I'd sooner face it alone.
It seems shocking for Anna
to find me en deshabille.
I'm made of stout stuff,
sir, don't worry about that.
Are you seeing Bates today?
I am, and I can't wait.
Give him our best wishes.
It still seems odd to
be found in your bed.
But very nice. Oh, as nice as nice can be.
I'm going to see Jarvis today
and find out what houses are
available. Do you have to?
These are our last days here. I
thought something might've turned up
while we were away but it seems it hasn't.
Would you rather wait till we have
to go and find a new house then?
After all, darling, you're
the one who's pushing us out.
(MAN) Not for me, thank you.
But Mary's only just
got back from honeymoon.
It's her family time. But you are...
Stop saying I'm family when I'm not.
I'll be there for the
big dinner next week.
What is it? I know you
don't mean to hurt me, but...
Of course I don't. That's
the last thing I'd wish to do.
Then why do you shove me away? I
don't want to, not at all, but...
If you're going to talk about your
wretched arm again, I won't listen.
It's not just my arm. I'm too old for you.
You need a young chap
with his life ahead of him.
Your life's ahead of you. If you
knew how much I want to believe that.
Then it's settled.
You're not going to push me away any more
and you are coming for dinner
tonight. That's all there is to it.
How did you get on with Vera's book?
I had a few answers waiting
for me when I got back
and two returned "address unknown".
Who from? Let me see, one
was a Mr Harlip, I think,
and the other was Mrs Bartlett.
He doesn't matter, he was a cousin
in the north, she never saw him,
but Mrs Bartlett's a shame.
She lived on the corner, she
was very friendly. I'll find her.
Tell me about France.
Did you eat frog's legs
and dance the can-can?
No, but I bought a garter.
You've had no other symptoms?
Not that I'm aware of.
You're not feeling ill or tired?
I can't swear to not feeling tired
but nothing out of the ordinary.
Very well.
I'm going to conduct a
preliminary examination.
Do you mind if I stay?
I should prefer it.
What have you got there?
Mr Matthew's tailcoat.
What do you think that is? Hard to say.
I've tried everything
but I can't shift it.
I'll give you a tip, if you
like. Would you, really? Yeah.
Keep it to yourself, don't want
to give away all my secrets.
Oh, there you are, my
dear. Good morning, Granny.
I've been looking for you.
Now I want to know if we're serious,
about getting that woman, about
asking your other grandmother
to come to our aid. She's made of money
and there's only Mama and Uncle
Harold to share it when she's gone.
We can't wait that
long, she'll bury us all.
No, we must act now.
We must make her feel it
is her duty to save Downton.
But how? What can we do?
Get her to sense its value,
its vital role in the area.
You're her granddaughter.
This will be your house if it survives.
Surely you can make something of
that if she has a heart at all.
We'll come for tea this afternoon.
Then we can begin.
There are several stages to go
through before a cause for despair.
What stages? When you
come back in a day or two,
I'll remove fluid from the cyst.
With luck it'll be clear
and that will be that.
How will you do it? With a syringe.
Will it hurt? Since he has to
do it, whether it hurts or not,
there's no point to that question.
What I want to know is what
happens if the fluid is not clear?
It'll be sent away for analysis.
Because it may be... cancer?
It may be cancer but I'm
fairly certain it is not.
There you are. It's very, very
unlikely, isn't it, Doctor?
If the doctor treats me like an adult,
why do insist on treating me like a child?
Does this seem slow to you? Not really.
Mrs Levinson's going to the Dower
House with the others for tea.
I think he likes me.
He's being friendly, that's all.
Are you all right? You seem to
have been slaving away for hours.
I want to be up to date before
I get back to the office.
Anything from Mr Swire's lawyer?
You can read it if you like.
(SIGHS) So you are
definitely Reggie's heir?
Looks like it, but if they
have to get a death certificate
out of the Indian authorities, it
won't be settled by Tuesday. Good.
Why is it good? The delay may
give you time to change your mind.
Stop punishing me, Mary, please.
If I accepted the legacy, I'd
take money under false pretences.
I'd be stealing. Your father
understands now why can't you?
He doesn't understand, he
just doesn't want to beg.
Anyway, I'm off to Granny's
for tea. See you later.
I do love you so terribly much.
Yes, I know you do.
So what's Harold doing now?
His idee fixe is yachts.
Bigger yachts, faster yachts.
Something with yachts.
Is he happy? He's much
too busy to find out.
It always seems so strange to
me that Cora has a brother. Why?
If there's a boy, the
daughters don't get anything.
There's no such thing as an
English heiress with a brother.
Why do we never see him?
Harold hates to leave America.
Curious. He hates to leave America.
I should hate to go there.
You don't mean that, Granny,
when we're both so drawn to America.
Indeed, indeed we are.
Never more than now,
when the bond between the Crawleys
and Levinsons is so strong.
That's nice, if you mean it, Mama.
I do.
It is marvellous the way our
families support each other.
You mean you needed the Levinson
cash to keep the Crawleys on top?
I'm not sure we'd put it that way.
I'm quite sure we would not. But
I hope you feel Mama's fortune
has been well spent in shoring
up an ancient family. Hm.
You gotta spend it on something!
What happened here? I...
I just...
You just what? There was a
mark. I know there was a mark,
but you didn't need to burn
it away. What have you done?
I'll go down in my dinner jacket,
send it to my tailor in the morning.
Come on, nobody's died,
just find the dinner jacket.
There don't seem to be any
glasses for the pudding wine.
Are they having one
tonight? It's on the menus.
I don't write them for my
own amusement. I dare say not.
I am trying, and so far failing,
to persuade his lordship to bring
the staff levels back up to snuff,
but until he does it is vital
that you pull your weight.
(SIGHS)
Newport's not a jungle, not at all,
but it is a little less formal.
Matthew obviously wants you to
feel at home in his play clothes.
Don't blame me. Alfred and
I had a disaster earlier.
What happened? He managed
to burn a hole in my tails.
Don't worry, it can be
mended. Careful, Carson.
I beg your pardon, my lord.
I like dinner jackets, sometimes
it's nice to be informal.
Especially when a couple is alone.
People like us should lead the
fight to keep tradition going.
If you mean we can never
change, I can't agree. Nor me.
Accepting change is as
important as defending the past.
The role of houses like
Downton is to protect tradition.
That's why they're so important
to maintain. Don't you agree?
We must do everything in our
power to keep Downton going. Sure,
if you think it's worth it.
Who's coming to dinner next week?
Locals. We thought you'd
like to see Downton on parade.
That's right. I'm glad
we've planned a dinner.
We can show you the real point of Downton.
I don't know what to say, Mr Carson.
What's going on here? Alfred
has embarrassed the family.
He forced Mr Matthew to appear
downstairs improperly dressed.
You make it sound quite exciting.
I will not tolerate vulgarity.
I'm sure Alfred didn't mean to. Hm.
I asked Thomas... Hey, what's
this? The stuff you gave me
burned a hole in the tails.
I gave you some soda crystals.
If you use them wrongly,
it's not my fault.
This is what comes of making
him run before he could walk.
If you want me to stay
away from her, I will.
I know it sounds harsh.
Please, I understand completely.
Edith's your daughter, you don't
want her seeing an old cripple.
Now you're the one who's harsh.
The trouble is she calls round regularly.
I can hardly ask her not to be admitted.
I suppose I could write to her.
I hope you won't feel we
can't be friends after this.
Let's leave it for a while. I'll
duck out of the dinner next week.
It might be best. Thank you.
That's the one you should've
taken, soda crystals.
But he didn't give me that, he
pointed to this one. I promise.
You don't have to promise, I believe you.
So you think he's not ready?
He's just a lad, my lord.
He can see to the odd visitor,
but permanent valet to Mr Matthew?
It's too much. I'm pretty sure Mr
Crawley'd rather manage on his own.
They wouldn't like that
downstairs, my lord.
I was afraid you'd say that.
So what would you suggest?
Ask Mr Molesley to join us.
It'd be kinder to Alfred in the long run,
kinder than asking more than he can give.
How is that poor footman? I
thought Carson would eat him alive.
Very glum. To be honest,
he has been a clot.
I'll have to send the coat to
London. Get it done quickly.
This dinner has to be
the grandest of the grand.
What do you hope to show
her? Why Downton matters,
why it mustn't fall apart.
Hasn't Cora had her
share of Levinson gold?
What's left is headed for your uncle.
He's as rich as Croesus as it is.
So you mean to fleece her? Since
you could get us out of this hole,
I won't take any criticism, thank you.
Will she do it? Granny will
make her or die in the attempt.
Now stop talking and kiss
me before I get cross.
You heard him, you'll know at once.
I wish you could get
those maids under control.
They've broken one of the
serving dishes this time.
We're short of a footman, a kitchen
maid and one house maid at least,
that's if Anna's to be a proper
lady's maid, what Lady Mary wants.
Naturally. She likes things done properly.
We can't do things properly until
his lordship allows us the staff
or until you and the blessed Lady Mary
come down from that cloud
and join the human race!
I can only suppose you
are over-tired. Good night.
You see, she... Good night, Mr Carson.
We will discuss the dinner in the morning.
Hm.
And no, Mrs Patmore, you may not tell him.
Oh. Have you finished with Mr Matthew?
I have. He's in the
dining room. You won't need
to attend to him again, Mr Molesley
is coming up from the village.
Has Mr Matthew complained?
It's not your fault,
we've hurried you along too
fast. You mustn't feel badly.
This is Thomas's doing,
but don't you fret,
I'll make him sorry.
I'm on your side.
I'm glad somebody is.
No Mary? She's a married woman now
so she can have breakfast in bed.
Hm. I'm sorry about your tails.
Carson's sending them up on
the London train this morning.
They'll have to put a new panel in.
We thought we'd get Molesley
to come and look after you.
He knows your ways. I'm perfectly happy...
I think it best if he comes. I must
talk to you about the staff we need.
Not now, Carson. Send for Molesley
if Mrs Crawley has no objection.
(SPOON CLATTERS)
Edith?
Oh, Papa, how could you?
(CRIES)
Crawley, do you know what that was?
I'm afraid I probably do.
I'm sorry but enough of my father's money
has already been poured into Downton.
Why should Harold lose half
his inheritance for our folly?
So it's all Papa's fault? It
isn't my mother's or brother's.
I don't see why they should
pay for it. We'll still ask.
What are you so afraid of? If we
sell, we move to a smaller house
and a more modest estate. We
don't have to go down the mine.
You don't understand. Mary, a lot
of people live in smaller houses
than they used to. Which shows
you're American and I'm English.
I shall be Countess of Grantham
one day and the Countess of Grantham
lives at Downton Abbey.
'What job might you be suited to?'
We're not here to give you food, we
want you to find your place in life.
Do you want to speak to me?
Yes, Mrs Crawley, I do.
Have you come for our help?
You're very welcome if you have.
Wait a minute, I know you.
You were the maid who brought your child
into the dining room at Downton.
Sorry, this has been a mistake.
I thought I was ready to ask
you but I'm not. I'm not ready.
Ask me what?
(DOOR OPENS)
I'm sorry to keep you waiting, ladies.
It's not quite as simple.
Oh, my God! Mrs Patmore, will you
please leave the hysteria to me?
I'm afraid the test was inconclusive.
I had hoped the fluid from the cyst
would be clear but there's blood,
not enough to confirm the presence
of cancer but too much to exclude it.
So what happens now?
I send it away for analysis and
this stage will take some time.
How much time? Anything up to two months.
Oh, my...
Until then, try to take it more easy.
Sit down and put your feet up if you can.
Chance'd be a fine thing.
Would you like me to say
something to Lady Grantham?
No, thank you, Doctor, I'll
speak to her myself if I need to.
Thank you.
(CRIES)
My darling girl, what's this?
I think you know, since you
asked Sir Anthony to write.
Edith, you understand I only
want what's best for you.
And you're the judge of that? In this.
Sybil marries a chauffeur
and you welcome him here,
but when I love a gentleman, you
cast him out. She has a point.
Strallan is certainly a gentleman.
Besides which he has a house,
he has money, a title,
everything that you care about.
You make me sound very shallow. Aren't you
when you make me give him
up because he has a bad arm?
He's quarter of a century too old.
Did she tell you that? Your
daughter is sad and lonely.
Now I don't mean to
interfere... Don't you?
If you ban him from Downton
I'll only go to his house.
I don't believe he'd see you.
I'll wait outside until he does.
How can you not like
him because of his age
when almost every man
we grew up with is dead?
Do you want me to spend my life
alone? I do like him very much.
So do I, Papa. So do I.
Please, ask him back.
He writes he's not coming to
Mama's dinner. Please make him.
Please, please, please.
Oh, all right, then.
I found Mrs Bartlett.
I wrote back to the tenant
of the house explaining
and they sent me a forwarding address.
I don't know why they didn't before.
But it doesn't mean she'll
talk to you. Why not?
Audrey Bartlett was the nearest
thing Vera had to a friend.
That's why I want to meet her.
She won't see the real Anna Bates.
She's doesn't have to like
me. I need her to be honest.
I'm going to write and ask for a meeting.
I can get to London and back in a day.
She won't agree.
I've the rent from the house,
I can make it worth her while.
Why do you think Vera
didn't go and see her instead
of sending that letter? Eh?
When Vera was frightened about your visit
she wrote that letter saying how
scared she was instead of seeing her.
Maybe she did both.
So...
what's the news at home?
I shouldn't tell you, really.
I haven't told any of the others.
It's breaking the code of a lady's maid.
His lordship's in trouble.
It seems he may have to sell.
What? Sell Downton?
That makes me sad.
I wouldn't have thought much could
touch me in here, but that does.
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
It hasn't come. They promised
and promised and I thought
it was sure to be on the
7 o'clock but it's not.
I'll just have to wear a black tie.
But Lady Mary, surely...
These things don't matter as much
as they did, Lady Mary knows that.
Thank you. I know I'm early...
Granny, come and see what we've done. Oh.
What do you think?
Nothing succeeds like excess.
When shall we tackle her? After dinner.
We'll get her on her own. She
wouldn't want to see all this go,
now it's for her granddaughter.
Never mistake a wish for a
certainty. Let's hope she won't.
Mrs Patmore. What is it
now? It's smoking, the range.
The wind's in the wrong
direction, rake it through.
Where's Alfred?! In the servants' hall.
Where are they? His what?
His bloody evening shirts!
Where have you put them? I
haven't touched them. Why would I?
Have you done this? Why would I
know anything about his shirts?
When I find out... Keep your
histrionics to yourself. Hurry up.
Her ladyship's in the drawing room.
His lordship's not even dressed?
You can't have lost them all.
I haven't lost any of them.
They've been taken by someone, stolen.
Why would they do that? To get at me.
Are you not popular downstairs?
I wouldn't say that, my lord,
but you know how people can be.
They like a little joke.
This is quite unacceptable.
If you uncover the
culprit, refer them to me,
but for now what are we going to do?
Good evening, Sir John.
It can't be going out. There
must be a block in the flue.
The dinner's not cooked, we
haven't put in the souffles.
There'll be no souffles tonight.
What on earth is going on?
We've 20 lords and
ladies in the drawing room
waiting for dinner and we've got
no dinner to give them. Oh, my God.
Why are you not in white tie?
I'm afraid they never sent my tails back.
You are not in white tie,
either. What have you come as?
I'm sorry, Thomas has lost my
dress shirts. Why is he still here?
I thought you gave him
his marching orders. I had.
My dear mother-in-law intervened.
I've a good mind to tell her...
No, she must have it
all her own way tonight.
You two are dressed for a barbecue.
I feel like a Chicago bootlegger.
That sounds almost as
peculiar as you look.
Come quickly. What is it?
The oven's broken down.
It can't have. What does that mean?
It means we have no food. Oh.
Funny clothes and no food.
Should be quite an evening.
Thank you, Mother.
Nothing's cooked and
nothing's going to be cooked.
But surely... Shall we
tell them to go home?
No, they've come for a party,
we'll give them a party.
Clear the table, go down to the larders,
bring up bread, fruit,
cheese, chicken, ham.
We're going to have an indoor picnic.
They're going to eat whatever
they want, wherever they want.
Are you quite sure, madam?
It's not how we do it.
How you used to do it.
It might be fun. I agree.
We'll all pull together
and it'll be great fun. Yes!
I know what we need. Does
anyone play the piano?
This is so not what we wanted it to be.
If it's the end of your undignified
campaign, I won't be sorry.
We can't just give up. Certainly not.
Do you think I might have a drink?
Oh, I'm so sorry, I
thought you were a waiter.
Slice that finely, fetch some
parsley, cut the dry bits off.
Can I lend a hand? I don't mind helping.
I think it's good to do other
things sometimes. I know you do.
There's not much left of this.
Cut it in squares, put it with ham.
You're very smart in your valet's outfit.
Alfred, check the meat larder,
bring anything back you think
a human being could swallow.
Chop, chop, Mrs Hughes. We can
rest later but not yet. Mr Carson...
Mr Carson's right, there's
not a minute to lose.
(SNIFFS) Psst!
Do you want to know a secret? The
shirts Thomas thinks he stole...
I saw who took them and
I know where they are.
Who did take them? Never mind that,
but I followed. I'll show you if you want.
Why are you being so nice to me?
Because I like you. And you
can say it, just like that?
I'm an American, Alfred, and this is 1920.
Time to live a little.
I thought you was trying to find
something about for Mrs Levinson.
Find out what when she reads
them like the palm of her hand?
She won't help, you know? Help with what?
Never mind. Just kiss me again.
Now, all of you find whatever
it is that you want to eat
and take it wherever you want to sit.
Anywhere? Anywhere.
If you have ever wanted to explore
Downton, this is your chance.
I'm sorry if it's all a
bit casual. It's exciting.
I feel like the bright young
people they write about.
Thank you, Lady Mellendorf. Cheer
up, she won't be here forever.
How much damage will
be done before she goes?
♪ Let me call you "Sweetheart"
♪ I'm in love with you
♪ Let me hear you whisper
♪ That you love me too
♪ Keep the love-light glowing
♪ In your eyes so true
♪ Let me call you "Sweetheart"
♪ I'm in love
♪ With
♪ You ♪
Is there anything for our supper?
I've taken a veal and egg pie.
Oh, I wish you'd let me talk to Mr Carson.
I don't want to be a sick woman in
his eyes for the next two months,
or a dying one in the
months to come after that.
(CRIES)
Shh. I know it'll be all right.
No, you don't,
but I appreciate the sentiment.
Are you sure you won't
wake up in ten years
and wonder why you're tied
to this crippled codger?
Only if you keep talking like that.
Do you know how much you mean to me?
You have given me back my life.
That's more like it.
You won't wait? To give you
the chance to change your mind?
Don't worry, I can get
it organised in a month.
Shall we tell them tonight?
No, no, I'll come back in the morning.
Can I ask you something? Why
do you like that American girl?
Steady. Who says I do? Don't you?
I suppose I do. And it
doesn't matter that she's fast
or that you won't see her
again after she's gone home?
She made me feel good about myself
for the first time here. Alfred!
Hurry up, I need you to
take around the claret.
Won't they spill it on the floor?
If you ask me, we are staring
into the chaos of Gomorrah,
but we have to give them more
wine and you are going to help.
What's that? I have to take
it upstairs for his lordship.
Well, be quick about it.
I'll help you any way
I can. Thank heavens.
It seems our family
owes Downton's survival
to the Levinsons not once but twice.
No. I'm so sorry, but
you've misunderstood me.
I cannot rescue Downton.
It's a shame if it has to go,
but I can't. But why not?
Because your grandpa tied the money down.
He felt the Crawley
family had quite enough.
But you said you'd help us.
I can entertain all of you
in Newport and in New York
and I can add to Cora's dress
allowance, but that's all.
My income is generous but
I cannot touch the capital.
Besides, Mary, the world has changed.
These houses were built for another age.
Are you sure you want to continue
with the bother of it all?
Quite sure. If I knew I was going to
lose it, I'd look on the sunny side.
Both of our husbands tied the money
up tight before they were taken.
Lord Grantham wasn't taken.
He died.
I suppose it's scraps
for the servants tonight?
Mrs Patmore's kept something by.
Who put them back?
What? The shirts, who put them back?
They're back? You mean you
overlooked them in the first place.
Don't tell me what I mean.
I'm warning you. You sound like
Tom Mix in a Wild-West picture show!
Stop warning me and go lay
out his lordship's pyjamas.
(TITTERS)
What are you laughing at? Those
missing shirts went for a walk
and now they've come
home. Really? Have they?
You didn't see nothing. I agree.
Cos if you did I'll cut ya.
Oh!
Don't ever threaten me.
I forgot I was sharing
a cell with a murderer.
Don't forget it again.
This evening has made
me homesick for America.
It's time to go.
I don't suppose you want
some whisky to take to bed?
Oh, but I'd love one. No water.
Thank you.
I'm sorry I can't help
you keep Downton, Robert.
That's what Mary wanted.
Ah.
I thought there was something.
You know, the way to
deal with the world today
is not to ignore it. If
you do you'll just get hurt.
Sometimes, I feel like
a creature in the wilds
whose natural habitat is
gradually being destroyed.
Some animals adapt to new surroundings.
It seems a better choice than extinction.
I don't think it is a choice.
I think it's what's in you.
Let's hope that what's in you
will carry you through these times
to a safer shore.
Is everything all right?
Certainly.
Was there something you wanted?
The kitchen managed well tonight
in difficult circumstances.
His lordship sent his thanks.
Was the evening a success?
The odd thing is I think it was.
For me, everyone sprawled on the floor
eating like beaters at a break
in the shooting isn't a party,
it's a works outing.
Where's the style, Mrs
Hughes? Where's the show?
Perhaps people are
tired of style and show.
Well, in my opinion,
to misquote Dr Johnson,
if you're tired of style,
you are tired of life.
Hm. Good night, Mr Carson.
You'd say if anything
was wrong, wouldn't you?
I know I've been a bit
crabby, but I am on your side.
Thank you for that.
You've just missed an admirer. Mr
Carson says you did well tonight.
Oh. Did you tell him?
No.
What is there to tell?
One day I will die.
And so will he. And you.
And every one of us under this roof.
(SIGHS)
You must put these things
in proportion, Mrs Patmore,
and I think I can do that now.
'Something happening in
this house is about me.'
'Strallan is the traditional choice.'
Edith is beginning her
life as an old man's drudge.
This is the moment you receive
a huge fortune to save Downton
and you give it away. I hope
you can understand... I'm trying.
Downton Place. Where am I to
go? We still own the village.
I could open a shop.
Fashionably late is one thing.
So it is Cancer? Don't say anything,
'she'd hate to think the doctor told you.'
itfc subtitles